

Kiev Ukraine E-mail: igorok.karpov@gmail.com Website: github.com/karpovigorok

Phone: +48-508-316-321

Telegram/WhatsApp: +380-95-795-58-87

Skype: igor.karpov.handmade

Born: 1982

I have a degree in computer science and more than 10 years of experience working in web development. I believe in Unit Tests and automation. I have experience working with Symfony, Laravel, Codelgniter, Zend Framework, MySQL, MongoDb and Memcached. I also experienced scrum master and Team Lead. I worked in the Ukrainian and foreign companies in the field of e-commerce, media, social media and trading.

Working Experience

FINALTO, PART OF PLAYTECH PLC

Web-developer

Feb 2015 — Now

Finalto is a hi-tech product company and a major service development center in the sphere of global dealing. Online CFDs trading platform. Working as part of B2B team.

- Implemented features and integrated with trading platform services
- Integrated new payment systems
- Developed integration with CRM
- · Worked with B2B customers and support existing
- Front end redesign of the trading platform markets.com

CIKLUM

Technical Lead for SolidMediaGroup

Feb 2013 — Dec 2014

High-Loaded project implemented on Symphony 2 framework, MongoDb and MySql.

Market web-based solutions that enable the customer to easily and professionally manage and analyze its corporate activities across multiple channels in social media

- Managing the team of developers (4 7 persons)
- Was engaged into development, took architectural decisions, worked on writing, rewriting and refactoring the code which is currently being used

DIGITAL VENTURES

Developer-Team Leader

Oct 2008 — Jan 2013

The company is owned by SCM Group, develops www.tochka.net portal.

- \bullet Managing the team of developers (5 7 persons), time planning (Planning Poker), conducting daily stand-up meetings, holding retrospectives, conducting product presentations, weekly self-education with the team
- Was engaged into portal development, took architectural decisions, worked on writing, rewriting and refactoring the kernel code which is currently being used on the portal
- Have implemented Jenkins continuous integration system in the development department in order to support the stability on production server

Web-developer

• Development from scratch and reworking the items: video, conferences, auto, sport, translator, mail, finance, fun, weather

HANDMADE INTERACTIVE

Web-developer

Jan 2007 — Oct 2008

Outsorsing American company.

• Development and maintenance www.celebritybabylon.com, www.jumpjet.com, www.robertkaufman.com, www.designsbytracym.com, www.teachoverseas.org, www.sexsmartfilms.com, www.collegeskoob.com

VIART

Web-developer

Jan 2006 — Dec 2006

Outstaffing British Company.

- · Developing web-based applications for e-commerce
- Writing front end and back end, automation of work and integration with Ebay and PayPal (through Ebay API, PayPal API)
- Interaction with paying systems; forum; file-manager; control version files, data import and export

NEWAGELAB

Web-developer

Jun 2005 — Dec 2005

Ukrainian web-studio.

Website development www.mercedes-benz.ua, www.gurt.org.ua, www.progerss.gov.ua, www.avtek.ua

LABORATORY F-4

Web-developer

Jun 2004 — May 2005

• Development of websites and administration systems for them zavodarsenal.kiev.ua, domovent.com

LABORATORY F-4

System administrator, maintaining of websites

Jul 2003 — Dec 2003

- Local network administration
- Maintaining and updating websites www.f4.org.ua, www.f4studio.net

Education

NTUU «KPI»

Software for automated systems

Kiev, Ukraine 2002 - 2008 Software engineer.

ZHELTOVODSKY
INDUSTRIAL TECHNICAL
COLLEGE OF DNU

Installation and operation of electrical equipment of enterprises and civil buildings.

Zhovty Vody, Ukraine 1998 - 2002

Professional skills

- PHP, JavaScript
- Frameworks: Codelgniter, Symfony2, Laravel, Zend Framework, jQuery, React
- APIs: Facebook API, Ebay API, Pay Pal API, Google Api
- MySQL, Sphinx, MongoDb databases design and optimization
- Git / Mercurial
- RabbitMQ queue manager
- Payment systems: authorize.net, 2Checkout.com, paypal.com
- CI: Jenkins, GitLab
- PHPUnit, Linkchecker
- Technologies: Ajax, Web-Services (SOAP, REST)
- HTML, CSS
- Linux experienced user

Have enough knowledge and experience of Scrum softeware development (performing functions of ScrumMaster) on Scrum.

Other

- https://github.com/karpovigorok my account on GitHub.
- habrahabr anonce speaker: "Continuous integration and deployment in web-projects"

Language skills

English Russian Ukrainian intermediate level native speaker native speaker